孙悟空你这个畜牲
Monkey King, you bastard
你本来答应如来佛祖
You've promised Buddha
护送你师父唐三藏去取西经
To help the Longevity Monk to get scriptures in the west
你竟然跟牛魔王串通要吃你师父
But the King Bull and you decided to eat your master
你知唔知道犯了弥天大罪啊？
Do you know you've made a real big mistake?
少啰嗦
Shut up!
你追了我三日三夜
You've followed me for 3 days
因为你是女人，我才不杀你
I didn't beat you up because you're a woman
不要以为我怕你啊
Don't think that I'm afraid of you
悟空
Monkey King
你怎么可以这样跟观音姐姐讲话呢？
be polite to Goddess!
不要吵
Shut up
你又在吓我
You scare me again
你不是怕我
If you're not scared of me
又为什么要打伤紫霞仙子？
you needn't hurt Purple Fairy
抢了她的月光宝盒呢？
and stole her Pandora's Box
你不就是想躲开我嘛
You just wanna escape
唉！既然躲不了
Now, I can't escape
老孙只有跟你决一死战
I will fight with you
要干什么？
What's up?
大家不要生气
Don't be angry
生气会犯了嗔戒的
You may violate the rule
悟空，你也太调皮了
Monkey King, you're so naughty!
我跟你说过
I've told you
叫你不要乱扔东西这么脏
not to throw things!
你看！
Look!
我还未说完，你把棍子又给扔掉了
You've thrown away the stick
月光宝盒是宝物
Pandora's Box is the treasure
你把它扔掉会染污环境
You'll pollute the environment
要是砸着小朋友那怎么办？
You'll hurt kids
就算没有砸着小朋友
If there are no kids
砸着那些花花草草也是不对的
it is bad to hurt plants
干什么？
What's up?
放手？
Let go!
你想要？
You want?
悟空，你想要就说话嘛！
Speak up if you want!
你不说我怎么知道你想要呢？
Why do you keep silent?
虽然你很有诚意的看着我
Although your eyes are full of sincerity
可是你还是要跟我说你想要的
I'm very glad, you still have to speak up
你真的想要吗？
Do you really like?
那你拿去吧
Take it
你不是真的想要吧？
Do you really like?
难道你真是想要吗？
You
我拷！
Damn!
孙悟空⋯
Monkey King….
大家看到啦
See
这个家伙没事就长篇大论
this guy keeps talking all the time
婆婆妈妈，叽叽歪歪
we don't know what he's talking about
就好像整天有一只苍蝇
He's just like a fly hanging around
对不起，不是一只
Sorry, not a fly
是一堆苍蝇围着你
It's a swarm of flies flying near your ears
还飞到你的耳朵里面
Flying into your brain
救命呀！
Help!
所以呢我抓住这只苍蝇挤破它肚皮
So I catch that fly. Open its belly
把它的肠子扯出来
Take out its intestine
再用它的肠子勒着它的脖子
Put its intestine around its own neck
用力一拉
Then I pull the intestine tightly
各位，整条舌头都伸出来了
The tongue comes out
我再手起刀落
I use a blade and cut!
哗！
Wow!
整个世界清静了
All the people keep silent
现在大家明白为什么我要杀它啦
Now you know why I need to kill
悟空，你诸多藉口
Monkey King, you have so many excuses
你根本不想去取西经
You don't want to get scriptures in the west
说那么多干什么，打吧！
Shut up please! Beat!
我老孙有金刚不坏之身
I've got a super body. You can't hurt me
十个观世音都不放在眼里
I don't scare of any god
今天我要替天行道
I'm destroy all devils
徒弟有错，做师父的也有责任
Being master, I should take the responsibility
求姐姐放他一条生路吧！
Please let him go!
我不消灭他，我无法同玉皇大帝交代
I have to do so, I need to report to Heaven Emperor
求姐姐跟玉皇大帝说一声
Goddess, please tell Heaven Emperor
贫僧愿意一命赔一命
I can sacrifice my life for him
喃呒阿弥陀佛⋯
Namonitabhaya…
到底他想说什么？
What did he say?
给他块肉
Give him the pork
大家小心点！
Stand by!
外面有个女人来
A woman is coming in!
二当家，你猜会不会是官兵呢？
Asst. Master, do you think soldiers are coming?
怪不得人家叫你瞎子啦
This is why you're called “Blind Bing”
你没看到哑巴屁股扭来扭去的吗？
Didn't you see Dumby shaking his ass?
扭来扭去的说不定长生痔疮呀？
Do you think he has hemorrhoids?
就算是有
OK, even if he has hemorrhoids
也是个长痔疮的官兵
he is a soldier with hemorrhoids
怕什么？
So what to be feared about him?
什么人？
Who the hell are you?
难道各位看不出我是个女人吗？
Don't you reckon I'm a woman?
你来这里干什么？
What do you come here for?
世途险恶，北风凛然
The world's gone mad
一个弱小女子
A weary lady
想找一个栖身之所歇息一下
looking for a shelter
洗洗身上的风尘
I wanna brush off the dust of my past
你知不知道这里是什么地方？
Do you know what place it is?
此处乌烟瘴气，各位又面目狰狞
This is not a nice place. You all look gruesome
绝不像是一家客栈
I don't think it is a decent tavern
莫非是一间黑店？
Is this a slaughter-house?
明知是黑店你还敢进来
Yes, we are. How dare you come in
你不怕送羊入虎口吗？
You're in danger already
谁是羊？谁是虎？
I'm not sure who's in danger
现在还言之过早
I think you're in danger
如果各位大爷是强盗
You can be robbers
难道就不怕我是强盗头吗？
So can I
你到底是何方神圣？
Who the hell you are?
桃花
Blossom
桃花过处，寸草不生
Nothing gets into my way and survives
金钱落地，人头不保
Money or your heads
春三十娘到五岳山来干什么呢？
Why does Ma'am 30th come to Mt Wuyue?
这个女魔头一向无宝不到
This devil is a fierce robber
难道这里会有大买卖？
Is here having big business?
你们这些笨蛋
Why do you still
还把银子顶在头上干什么？
put the money on your head?
放下来！
Put it back!
不行！金钱落地，人头不保啊，帮主
She said it is our head or the money, Master
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
二当家
Asst. Master!
你这么没种怎么当我二当家？
You coward! How can you be my assistant?
帮主，我不是二当家，我系瞎子啊
Master, I'm not Asst. Master! I'm Blind Bing!
他才是二当家啊！
He is Asst. Master
对啊！我才是二当家呀
Yes, I'm Asst. Master
我骂瞎子是要你惭愧
I will make you regret!
你还不跑！
Go away!
看看你的德性，鬼鬼祟祟，丢人现眼
Look at yourself. Mousing around, so shameful
披头散发！人模狗样
How can you follow me around with their hair?
怎么跟我出来闯荡江湖啊呀？呀？
帮主，我在这里啊！
Master, I'm here!
还不现身？
Come out!
现身了，帮主
Coming
你中了昆仑三圣的七伤拳
Master, you're hit by Kunlun Sage's 7 Ultimate Fists
现在伤势开始发作
Your wounds are spreading
你还敢说
Shut up
那天不是你把脖子缩了一下
you knelt down that time
我会被人家打中鼻子吗？
and I got hit in the nose
这边啊，帮主
Master, here!
七伤拳把帮主害得真惨
The 7 Ultimate Fists really hurt Master
帮主，我当时是吓得跪下来嘛
Master, I was scared, so I knelt down
我听说中了七伤拳
It is heard that people who got hit by the 7 Ultimate Fists
首先是变斗鸡眼
will have disease in his eyes
然后耳朵失聪，聪不到声音
Then he'll become dumb
之后声线失控，说话全部都走音
After that he can't speak properly
最后五脏六腑爆炸，然后就死定了！
At last, his body explodes and he's dead
帮主，你斗鸡眼很严重啊！
Master, there's something wrong with your eyes!
谁说我斗鸡眼啊？
I am OK!
我只是把视力集中在一点
I only concentrate my eyesight on a single point
以改变我以往对事物的看法！干嘛？
I only change my usual way of vision
造谣我不行了，想抢我的位子呀？
Do you want to take my position?
不敢帮主，不敢呀
No, Master, I don't dare
我踩死你，不敢
You don't dare? I am gonna kill you!
我踩！
Kill you!
我踩那么久，就算不痛也呻吟两声嘛
Can you cry out for me?
收到⋯啊！⋯
Ah….
好！大家准备带着家伙去找⋯
Ok, let's get our weapons and search
春三十娘
Ma'am 30th
怕什么！万事有我！
No need to scare! I'm here!
在下斧头帮帮主
I'm the leader of the Axe Gang
外号玉面飞龙至尊宝
My nickname is Joker
久闻春三十娘大名，如雷贯耳
It is nice to meet famous Ma'am 30th
请问春三十娘光临敝帮
What are you gonna
有何贵干呢？
do here?
我要在这个地方逗留片刻
I just wanna stay here for a while
不知片刻是多久？
A while? How long is it?
三天两夜
3 full days
也有可能是三、五、十年
Maybe 30 or 50 years
总之等到我要等的人出现
I'll leave when I meet the person
我就会离开
who I want to see
我怕你没那么长命
I don't think you can wait so long
你干什么？
What are you doing?
小完便穿裤子
I've just had a piss!
你在这里小便？
You had a piss here?
不然你哪来这么大缸水洗澡啊？
This is why you have so much water to bathe
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
我话你没那么长命等到你要见的人
I said live to see that person
帮主⋯
Master…
想杀我没那么容易
I'm not that easy to kill
先问过我的兄弟们
Ask my brothers first
没义气啊！
You have no guts…
你们这些吃里扒外的家伙
You betray me!
天呀！
God!
你有本事就把我们全杀光！
Kill us all if you can!
饶命呀⋯
Forgive me…
饶命呀，女英雄
Forgive me, heroine…
白痴！你以为她就会放过你吗？
Stupid! Do you think she will let you go?
无论说什么也要跟她拼了
I'm gonna fight
听到了没有？
even if I lost my life!
男儿膝下有黄金！既然他们肯求我
That's fine. Since you're willing to beg me
那么性命暂时寄存在我这里
I won't kill you now
谢谢女英雄！
Thanks a lot!…
至于你嘛⋯你可真有骨气
You…you're so righteous!
孺子可教
You're so good!
叫他们把脚底板洗干净在外面等我
You all clean your soul and wait for me outside
怎么会有块疤？
Why is there a scar?
这不是疤啊，这只是肮脏啊
This is not a scar, it is only dirt
马上去洗干净
Go clean it
不然的话我把它砍下来
or I'll cut the whole leg off
帮主啊
Master
她为什么要看我们的脚底板呢？
why she wanna see our soles?
幸亏只是看脚板，而不是看屁股呢
It is lucky that you don't wanna see our ass
你怕啊？
Are you scared?
是你怕啊，不是我怕！
I'm not! You are scared!
为什么？
Why?
你屁股长了那么多痱子
You have hemorrhoids
说不定会说你不干净
She'll say they are not clean enough
要把它切掉啊！
and cut them off
你怎么知道我屁股⋯
Why do you know I have hemorrhoids?
瞎子说偷看你洗澡看到的
Blind Bing peeped on your shower
你干嘛偷看我洗澡啊？
Why did you peep on me?
我不止偷看你一个
I not only peeped on you
所有人我都偷看过了
I've peeped on you all
怎么会这么多毛啊？
Why is there so much hair?
正常啊！
Sure
我身体上其他地方的毛更茂盛
I've got more in other parts
怎么样？
What?
是不是看得你心痒痒？
Are you excited now?
哼！你说那里长得更茂盛啊？
Where did you say has more hair?
不是呀！
No
其实我只是头上跟脚底板有毛
in fact I only have hair on my head and sole
大概是长错地方了
Do you think they grow on the wrong places?
从今天起，我要你不分昼夜
From now on, I'll check all the people
查看所有经过这里的人
passing here!
查什么？
Check what?
查他们脚底板
Check their sole
如果发现有三颗痣的，立即通知我
If you discover a guy having three birthmarks, tell me
帮主呀！我们不是抢劫
Master! We don't go to rob
光看人家的脚底板
but check people's soles
要是被同行知道，会笑我们变态啊
If the others know that, they'll say we're perverts
明刀明枪斗不过她，暗箭她就难防
We can plot against her
今夜三更用五毒迷晕香让她尝尝
Poison her, make her faint
先奸后杀！
then rape and kill her!
好计谋！
A good plot!
你也觉得好吧
You think so
这个任务就交给你去执行
You shall administer the plan
这么看得起我，算了吧！
I don't think I can do this
不用了，帮主，不用下跪了
I go, no need to kneel down
你以为我想跪啊！是我的腿不听使唤
I don't want to! I can't control my legs
帮主，你七伤拳的伤势越来越严重了
Master, your wound is worsening
我还有双手
I still have both hands
我不会屈服的
I won't give up!
帮主掉粪坑去了
Master has fallen into a shit pit!
帮主呀！
Master!
你找到三颗痣没有啊？
Have you found the three birthmarks?
为什么每个人都叫我找三颗痣？
Why does everyone tell me to find the three birthmarks?
找到你就可以救他了
You can save him when you find them
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
这里到底是什么地方？
Where are we?
什么人？
Who?
做梦
Dreaming
把那贱人干掉了是吗？
Did you kill that bitch?
蜘蛛！蜘蛛呀！⋯
Spider! Spider…
蜘蛛用得着大惊小怪的？
It's only a spider
好大只呀！
It's big
能有多大啊？
How big is it?
我早就叫你们平常好好打扫干净
I've told you to tidy up the place
现在养出来的蜘蛛比我还大！
The spiders are bigger than me
怎么办？
What should I do?
糟了！这么多人它不追，老是追着我
It keeps running after me
一定又是我的英俊害着我
Maybe I'm handsome
干什么？
What?
什么事？
What's up?
帮主被蜘蛛追呀？
A spider is running after Master?
是不是这样啊？　　不是⋯
This way? No…
是这边！这边！
This way!
好了，快！
Fine, be quick!
有没有搞错？
How come?
救命呀！
Help!
来人呀！我在这里呀！
Come here! I'm here!
快！
Be quick!
我在这里！
I'm here!
救命呀！
Help me!
瞎子！
Blind Bing!
前面什么都没有，大家快回头！
Nothing in the front! Turn back, turn back!
谁说的！前面是帮主啊
No! It's Master! Master…
是吗？不是蟑螂吗？
Isn't it a cockroach?
前面是帮主呀
It's Master
好！上
Great! Go!
你们这些王八蛋，骗我的
You sons of bitches, deceive me
帮主，我来救你
Master, I'm coming
什么东西啊？
What am I touching?
救了帮主了⋯
Master is saved…
二当家那么开心扛着什么东西走啦？
Asst. Master is so happy. What is he holding?
帮主，他扛的不是你吗？
Master, didn't he carry you out?
帮主啊⋯回家了⋯
I'm fine, let's go home…
待会洗个澡，早点睡
Take a bath, go to bed sooner
晚上不要到处乱跑
Don't hang around tonight
放手！
Let go!
蜘蛛呀！
Spider!
瞎子
Blindy
帮忙
Help
谁帮呀？
Who?
烧它⋯！
Burn it!
不行了，得休息一下才行
Have a rest first
烧它！
Burn it!
别让他跑了⋯烧它
Don't let him go…burn it
烧它！
Burn it!
走开，怕什么呢？
No need to be frightened
烧它！
Burn him…
在那里呀⋯
He's there…
在这边，快追⋯
It's over there, go there…
这里还有一只
Here is another
这只小一点
This one is smaller
还跑？
Freeze!
在哪里啊？
Where?
好像在那边
It's there!
追呀！
There!
剩下两只爪子，等我中间把你劈开
Only two claws are left. Let me break you in half
去死！
Go to hell
你不要跑
Don't go!
在这边！
It's here
打它⋯！
Beat it!
拿过来
Give it to me
通通让开！等我来烧死它！
All spread out! Let me burn it!
去死啦！
Go to hell!
着火了！
Burning!
烫死我了！
Very hot!
怎么好像帮主的声音呢？
It's Master's voice
救命呀！
Help!
快救帮主
It's Master. Help him!
真的是帮主！
It's Master
救命！
Help!
救火，帮主你小弟着火了！
Master, your cock is burning
快⋯
Be quick
快点拿水来
Get the water…
救火⋯
Put out the fire
快救火了！
完蛋了
Dying!
快点呀！
Be quick
大家都来救火，怎么可少了我呢？
I'm going to put out the fire, too
你们让开，让我来
You can't put out the fire with straw. Stay away!
帮主，踩熄了
Master, it's OK!
你别怕，我踩熄了！
I'll put it out!
踩熄了，踩⋯
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop burning…
踩得你死挠挠！
Out you go…!
踩死你！
Stop burning!
不行了⋯
I can't take this…
怎么样？舒坦了吧？
The fire is out! Are you OK?
这个灭火呢得要这样踩才会灭！
You have to step on him and put the fire out
这个常识你们都没有吗？
Moron!
是谁烧我？
Who burned me?
不是我啊！
Not me!
不知道啊！
I have no idea
我早猜到是你！
I know it's you!
我早就看穿你的心、肝、脾、肺、肾！
I know what you're thinking!
是想坐我的位子，对不对？
You wanna take my place!
没有啊，帮主
No…Master…
帮主没有斗鸡眼了！
Master's eyes are Ok.
我真的没有呀
No, I didn't do that
帮主，你七伤拳全好了
Master, you've recovered
对啊！为什么呢？
I'm cured! Why?
我明白了！
I know!
治七伤拳的方法是要以毒攻毒
You must hurt yourself in order to
伤上加伤
cure the wounds
有道理！
It's reasonable!
至于二当家呢，他是无心之失嘛
You have to thank Asst. Master
如果不是他踢你小弟弟两脚
If he didn't hit you at the crotch
这伤也不会这么快就治好啊！
you won't be healed so fast
你这么维护他，是不是跟他有一腿？
Do you have an affair with him?
人家对你一条痴心嘛
I love you so much
去你妈的！发春呀？
Go to hell! Stop it !
二当家，叫你杀春三十娘
I've told you to kill Ma'am 30th.
你搅定了没有？
Have you done that?
春三十娘系妖怪啊
Ma'am 30th is a devil!
蜘蛛精呀！
Spider Woman!
老弟啊，这么有理性的人
I'm a rational man
怎么能够接受这么无稽的事情呢！
I can't accept such ridiculous thing!
杀了她
Kill her!
帮主，你就这么去？你不怕？
Master, aren't you scared?
怕什么？我的伤都全好了
Of course not! I'm healed.
还怕砍不过她？
I will defeat her!
好！有种！
Great! You have guts!
你说有种，是不是？
You said I had guts?
是啊，就当我没说好了
Yes, but forget I'd say that
帮主
Master
那你就随便拿件家伙冲进她房间里乱砍
You just get into her room and finish her off
我们后面掩护你
We'll cover you up!
为什么每次都是我先⋯
Why do I go first everytime…
掩护我靠近点行不行啊？
You said you would cover me up so stay closer
你放心啦！
Steady
我们这里几十把家伙保护着你
we've got weapons
一不对劲就全扔过去啦
We'll throw them at her
那我不是也完蛋了吗？
You'll kill me, too
傻瓜！
Don't be silly!
大不了重伤！要死那么容易吗？
You won't die, you'll only get hurt!
混蛋！
Sons of bitches!
起来！你少在我前装蒜
Get! You are not fooling me
我告诉你
Listen to me
少来这一套
Stop that
真的晕倒了？
Fainted?
大牛、二虎
Big Cow, Younger Tiger
散得真快，我自己来
You're all useless. Let me do this
怎么样？
What?
你刚才真的装昏？
You faked the fainting?
这一招叫做忍辱偷生
This is a tactic.
大腿挨一刀算得了什么？
It is very useful
那儿漏水？
Where is the leak?
二当家，不是漏水，是你流血啦
Asst. Master, you're bleeding
不要怕⋯
Don't scare!
我只要点我曲池，急宫两个穴道
I can stop the bleeding
血马上就停止
by myself
这里算不上山明水秀
it's not picturesque
可是也别有一番风味
but it is unique
两位住在这里一定会爱上它
You may love this place, eventually
晚安！
Good night!
帮主，怎么样？⋯
Master…
怎么样？是不是妖怪？
She is a devil!
是！
Yes!
而且非常的妖！
She is a real devil!
弄得我心卜通卜通乱跳
My heart is pounding!
帮主请留步
Master, stop it!
师姐说，帮主大仁大义，是侠中之侠
You're a righteous man, a hero
能交上帮主你这样的朋友
It is my pleasure
真是三生有幸
to be your friend
今天搁在你兄弟们头上的钱
The money put on your bros’ heads
就当请大家去买酒喝吧
is all given to you to buy drinks
多谢三十娘一番美意
Thank you very much, Ma'am 30th
帮主，品味太差了吧？
Master, she's not really good-looking
各有所好嘛
But I like her!
大腿扎一刀嘛，浑身都是洞
Only thrust the thigh once, but there are so many holes
什么意思嘛？
What do you mean?
师姐，怎么突然不辞而别
Sister, why did you leave?
跑到这种穷乡僻壤的地方？
You ran to this poor village
还被一群老粗
and you're forced to reveal
用迷药把你弄得原形毕露
your real image
你来干什么？
What are you doing here?
你呢？
How about you?
我想出来散散心
I just want to have a walk
你想在这里等唐三藏出现
You're waiting for the Longevity Monk
尝佢长生不老之肉
you wanna eat his flesh
你能从菩提老祖口中
You can make Granpa Buddha
骗他说出这个天机
speak out this top secret
难道我就不能吗？
So do I
胡说！
Nonsense!
胡说？那么你跑到五岳山来干什么？
Nonsense? Why did you come to Mt Wuyue?
这里以前叫做五指山
This was called “Fingers Mountain” in the past
是那只死猴子当年被困之地
It's the prison for this monkey
天机泄漏他会转世为人
The top secret says that he'll become human
在投胎之后脚底板会有三颗痣
and he has three birthmarks on his sole
只要找到他就可以找到唐三藏
you can find the Monk if you know where Monkey King is.
师姐，我这么说不知道算在胡说吗？
Sister, do you still think I'm speaking nonsense?
是你想再看那只臭猴子吧
You just want to see that monkey
再看到那无情无义的人怎么样
You can do nothing even if you see him
不同的是他上次死在观世音手上
The difference is that he died in Goddess's hands last time
这一次却会死在我手上
but he died in my hands this time
一个和尚有水喝
It will benefit
两个和尚没水喝
only one person
这个道理你都不懂？
You know the reason!
想跟我争
Do you wanna fight over him with me?
你以为只有你会变？
Do you think only you can fake face?
谁？
Who?
妖怪⋯！
Devil…!
你看到什么？
What did you see?
没什么
Nothing
没有！
No!
那你蹲下来干什么？
What are you doing down there?
我结鞋带
I wanna tie the lace
如果唐僧这个消息传出去了
If the secret of the monk leaked
我第一个就把你给杀了
I'll kill you
到时候群妖会合五指山
Then, all devils gather at Fingers Mountain
向师姐讨块唐僧肉吃就行吧！
beg for the flesh of the Longevity Monk
把唐三藏这个消息报告给大王
Tell the King about this
一定重重有赏
he will bestow on us
连牛都开口说话，这次真是百妖交集
Even a bull is talking. So many devils here this time
赶快走⋯
Go…go away
这样走太不讲义气了！
If I go now, I'm a coward!
对！报告帮主
No, report to Master
帮主
Master
原来我们这里五岳山
This mountain was called
就是以前的五指山
Fingers Mountain in the past
唐僧跟孙悟空在这儿会合
The Longevity Monk and the Monkey King will meet here
我们牛栏的牛居然开口说话了
My bull is talking
这两个家伙
Those two things
一个有八只手，一个的头头头⋯
one has 8 legs, one's head…
两位还没睡啊？
You two haven't slept?
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
没什么
ah…
我们猪栏的母猪生了两只小猪
Two baby pigs are born
一只呢有八⋯八只脚
One has 8 legs
另外一只的头有四百多斤重
One has a very heavy head
帮主，这一次我们发了
Master, we're rich now
我们以后不要再做贼了
We needn't be robbers anymore…
我们哪有养猪啊？
We didn't rear any pigs
我们没有养猪吗？
We didn't rear any pigs?
也许我在做梦，我瞎掰的
Or I'm speaking in my dream !
我走了！我不打扰你们休息了
OK, I'm leaving, please take a rest
我们也走了
We're leaving
顺便送两位姑娘出去
Walk both girls away
不行！
No!
两位，明天我一定派相关人等
I will order someone to search for
在这里附近彻底搜查你们要找的人
the guy you wanna see
谢谢帮主
Thank you master
帮主晚安！走啦
Good night! Go!
去！去！
Go! Go!
这下没搞头了
Nothing can be done this time
为什么晶晶姑娘对我这个造型
Why does Jing Jing have no reaction
完全没反应呢？
to this image?
没办法
Nothing I can do
走！
Go!
不要杀我！⋯不要杀我！
Don't kill me!…Don't kill me!
我跟你们玩玩的
I just wanna have fun with you
喜欢玩是吧？
Do you like playing?
我们就玩吧！
Come and have fun
好不好玩呀？
Is it funny?
好玩
Yes!
好玩再玩一次
Ok, let's play again
还玩不玩呀？
Play again?
不玩啦⋯
I don't wanna play….
刚刚谁说看到有八只爪啊？
You said who's got eight claws?
我不记得了⋯
I can't remember it…
干嘛？
What?
不要啊！
No!
我的头是不是这样子的？
My head looks like this?
是呀，是呀！
Yes…! Oh no!
是什么嘛？她还没有变
She's not changed yet
这还没变
Not yet?
一刀杀了他
I'll kill him
不行
No
为什么？
Why?
我要用移魂大法迷住他
I'm gonna mesmerize him
留他来做我的卧底
he'll be my undercover agent
嗨！
Hi
鬼呀！
Ghost!
过去看看
Go to have a look
这么英雄潚洒你说有鬼！
You said a ghost!
真是没见过世面
Oh dear!
啫！老大不小的，还给我装蒜
Don't be pretentious around here
等一下我一块肉一块肉地给你割下来
Or I will cut you into pieces
不会那么残忍吧？
You're so brutal!
看着我
Look at me!
移魂大法
Mesmerizing!
什么人？
Who?
长夜漫漫，无心睡眠
It's a long night, no mood to sleep
我以为只有我睡不着觉
I thought I was the only one
原来晶晶姑娘你也睡不着啊？
But Jing Jing, you're sleepless, too?
是呀！不知道帮主为什么睡不着？
Yes, why can't you sleep?
就系因为晶晶姑娘你
Just because of Jing Jing!
我？
Me?
没错！自从看到晶晶姑娘之后
yes, when I saw you
我决定改过自新，不再做贼
I made up my mind that I wouldn't be a robber
为了表示对姑娘你的诚意
I just wanna show my sincerity
我不要再看见以前的我
I can't face my past
好看吗？
Like what you see?
是你这臭猴子？
You're monkey?
臭猴子？
Monkey?
孙悟空
Monkey King
孙悟空？
Monkey King?
你变成人样就行了吗？
You think you're alright with a human face?
人样？
Human Face?
看来我用三味白骨火，你是不会承认
I have to use Skeleton Fire on you
哗！还用得着！又烧！
You gonna burn me again!
何必呢？
Why?
难道我搞错了？
Did I make a mistake?
何必呢？
Why?
你干嘛用火焰来烧我？
Why did you use flame bomb to burn me?
你把胡子剃光干什么？
Why did you shave off your beard?
你知不知道你少了胡子
You're just another guy
一点性格都没有啦？
without the beard
是吗？
Really?
文也不行，武也不行
You can't do anything
你不做山贼，你想做状元吗
Do you want to be a scholar instead of a robber?
我想过啊，不过
I've thought about this
省省吧你，改变什么形象
Please stop changing image
好好的做你山贼这份很有前途
being a robber is
的职业嘛
a good job
我知道了
I know
我一定会继续努力的
I'll try my best!
什么不好像，像个臭猴子
You look like that thing!
真失败
So pathetic
原来晶晶姑娘喜欢我粗犷的一面
Jing Jing loves my violent side
乱是乱了点，总算回复了几分风采
Having the personality again
孙悟空，你给我滚出来
Monkey King, come out!
你个臭猴子
Damn monkey
我十八岁那年你说会来娶我
You said you would marry me when I was 18
害我把他等了三年
I have waited for you 3 years
你给我滚出来
You come out!
我们大王有事出去了
Our King is not here
他说白姑娘的话，把这东西还给她
He said give it to Miss Pak when you come here
还说感谢白姑娘的美意
and thanked Miss Pak very much
他就无福消受了
He can't enjoy it
五百年了⋯
500 years…
我终于找到唐三藏的踪迹了
We've found the Longevity Monk at last
连脚底板的毛也剃光了
The hair on the sole has been shaved off
不知道要哪一年才长得出来
I don't know when it will grow again
糟了！被那两个家伙先到一步！
Shit! They come first!
我菩提老祖一定要想个办法通知
I have to inform
这群无辜的人
these innocent people
你又回水帘洞来啦？
You come back to Waterfall Cave again?
什么？水帘洞？
Waterfall Cave?
你是谁你？
Who are you?
怎么老是带我来这里干嘛？
Why do you bring me here?
没有人带你来，是你自己要回来
No one brings you here. You come here on your own
一个人离开家太久了，总是想回家
It is normal to miss your home
你不要耍我
Don't tease me!
我的家在五岳山第四边101号B1
My home is at Mt Wuyue
你搞错啦，你听到没有？
You have made a mistake, can you hear me?
以后不要再烦我啦，拜托！
Don't annoy me, please!
出发了帮主，不然会迟到啦
We have to go, Master, or we'll be late.
出什么发啊？
Go? What do you wanna do?
抢劫呀，帮主
Robbery!
谁敢跑来抢劫啊？
Who dares to do so?
我们去抢劫人家啦
We go to rob!
我知道啦！　出发！
OK, that's fine!
抢劫啊⋯
Go to rob…
抢劫什么？
What?
脚底板啊，老爷
Rob the sole.
我没有脚啊，怎么办啊？
I have no legs. What to do?
看什么看？
What are you looking at?
嘴刮干净就英俊多啦，妒忌呀？
Are you jealous of my handsomely shaved face?
干干净净很好啊
That's fine
是啊⋯
Yes…
妒忌就妒忌嘛！
Jealous! You guys…
还嘴硬！
Shut up!
葡萄？
Grapes?
帮主，葡萄已经洗干净了
Master, the grapes are washed
出去
Go out
晚饭已经准备好了
The dinner is ready
出去
Go out!
谁啊？
Who?
我就是你带回来的那串葡萄
I'm the grapes that you bring here!
你就是葡萄？
You're grapes?
不是！我系菩提老祖
No, I'm Grandma Ada?
什么菩你老母？
What Grandma Ada?
你占我便宜
Stop the nonsense.
我是菩提老祖，我是神仙
I'm Grandpa Buddha, an immortal
我化为葡萄来救你的
I turned myself into grapes and saved you
你偷了我的葡萄，还菩我老母？
You stole my grapes and forbid me mentioning Grandma
那两个女人是妖怪
Both women are devils
如果你不相信
If you don't believe me
我的照妖镜一照，你就会明白了
you can use my Magic Mirror!
我照你老母的妖镜
I use your Mom's mirror!
说　　你听我说
Say! Listen to me
你是不是偷了我葡萄？
Have you stolen my grapes?
我没有啊！
No!
没有？那我的葡萄到那儿去了？
Where are my grapes?
我就是葡萄了！
I'm your grapes!
大声点
Louder!
我就是你的葡萄
I'm your grapes
为什么不做苹果？要做葡萄
Why aren't you an apple?
你跟我说
Listen to me
你别以为我打不过你
You shouldn't think I can't defeat you
我只是不想伤及无辜
I don't wanna hurt innocent people
来呀！
Go out!
我打你这个老糊涂
You will be seriously hurt!
晶晶姑娘
Jing Jing!
你的胡子好粗犷呀
Your beard looks great!
是吗？
Really?
乒拎乓啷的是什么声音？
Why was it so noisy?
我刚刚在打一串葡萄
Just beating the grapes
那里会有人打葡萄的？
Who're gonna beat grapes?
吃饭吧
Meal time.
吃饭了
Meal time
吃饭好啊
That's great!
好是吗？
Great?
我看今天月亮这么美，不如⋯
What a pretty moon. Let’s…
月光？没有啊？
Moon? I can't see it
那么大的月亮你没看到吗？看清楚点
There is a big moon. Can you see it?
天还没有黑，那来的月光
It's not dark yet, how come is there a moon?
你说啊⋯
Tell me…
哎菩什么老母？
Who? Who the hell…!
菩什么老母？
Who the hell?
我变成葡萄了
I was turned into grapes
你在哪里啊？
Where are you?
我在你的裤裆里面
In your trousers
哗！这么大一串？
Big grapes!
那串是你的，我在你后面
It's yours. I'm at your back!
再见到你太好了
That's great to see you
你现在相信啦！
You trust me now!
我相信了，相信了
Yes, I trust you
我这里怎么会有妖怪出现啊？
Why do we have devil here?
笨蛋啊，我告诉你吧！
Stupid fool, listen to me
这群妖怪呢是等唐三藏重现人间
These devils are waiting for the Longevity Monk
唐三藏重现人间？
Longevity Monk?
五百年前孙悟空被观音大士所消灭
500 years ago, Monkey King was destroyed by Goddess
他师父唐三藏为了救他
His master Longevity Monk wanted to save him
用自己的性命
He exchanged the monkey's life
换取孙悟空一次重生的机会
with his own
希望这只猴子能改邪归正
He hoped this monkey would be good
唐三藏为什么在这里出现
Why does the Longevity Monk
你还没告诉我？
need to appear?
不错！唐三藏当年为了普渡众生
he wanted to save the whole world
不怕千辛万苦去取西经
so he went to India and tried to get scriptures
希望藉此经书来感化世人
he hoped they would do good to the people
满天神佛都被他这种精神所感动
All devils were impressed by his spirit
玉皇大帝眼见如此
heaven Emperor saw that
因此给孙悟空一个机会转世
He gave the monkey a chance to revive
安排他们师徒今世在这里重逢
He planned the master and the disciple to meet here
继续去完成取西经的使命
Then they can finish the journey to the west
为什么那么多妖在这儿出现
Now, you know why there are so many devils here
你明白了
You got it
怪不得我长久以来都在做同样的
So I am having the same
一个恶梦
dream
在一片漆黑孤独的环境里头
In a pitch-dark area
一对一对非常迷迷的眼睛
a pair of seductive eyes
一直盯着我看
looking at me
看得我都非常不好意思
make me embarrassed
就是你这种眼神
Your eyes look like the eyes in my dream
有好几次盯得我脸都红了
Sometimes, my face becomes red
原来注定我今天撞妖！
I have to face the devils tonight!
对呀！你今天真是撞妖了
Yes! You are facing devils tonight!
这两个乾坤袋，一叠隐身符
Two Magic Bags here, and some invisible stickers
你把符贴在身上，她们就看不到你了
You're invisible if you stick one on your body
趁她们不注意，你就套在他们头上
Cover him by it when he is not aware
去吧！我在后面掩护你
I'll cover you up from the back
你这句对白一直都是我说的
This is my line!
你跟谁说的？
Whom are you talking to?
跟他
To him
对啊！我当然帮你
Let me help you!
了不起！不愧是我的好哥们
That's great! You're my good bro
你现在出去叫所有兄弟进来
Tell all bros to come in
每个人给一道符
give a magic sticker to each of them
我回菩提老祖那儿拿乾坤袋来
I go back to get the Magic Bag
我们一起抓妖怪
Then we can catch all the devils
没问题
No problem
好哥们
Good brother
你今天的眼神这么⋯
Your eyes today…
淫荡吗？
Are they seductive?
对啊
Yes
我一定帮你的
I will help you
两位，请慢用
Help yourself!
怎么办？
What to do?
有什么办法，是帮主吩咐的
It is Master's order
那你也得想个办法
You wait a moment
二当家
Asst. Master
通知其他人，帮主找我们
Tell the others, Master is looking for us
快去⋯
Go
隐身符
Invisible sticker
走吧⋯
Go…
师姐
Sister
知道了⋯
OK….
我们不动声色，看看他们想干什么
Let's keep quiet and see what they want
师妹，喝酒呀！
Sister, drink!
师姐，你也喝
Sister, you drink too
你怎么啦？
What are you doing?
我有点醉，我想睡一下
I'm drunk. I wanna sleep
不用怕，看不到的
don't be afraid. We're invisible
不能喝就别喝嘛，真是丢人
You shouldn't drink so much if you cannot drink
真的看不到
We're invisible
你本来就看不到
You can see nothing all the time
走
Ok!
怪了，帮主怎么还没来
Master hasn't come yet
就是
Yes
不是说有烤鸡嘛？
You say there is roast chicken
帮主！着火啦
Master! It's burning
不能脱
Don't be naked.
快还钱啊，混蛋！
Pay me back! Fool!
你说就说，干什么那么凶呀？
No need to be like that?
我凶不行啊？借了钱不用还哪？
None of your business, pay me back
你放屁，我什么时候跟你借了
When did I borrow money from you
是你欠我钱呀？
You owe me
我欠你？
I owe you?
怎么？不记得了吧？
Don't you remember?
对啊！
No….
没记性
You lost your memory
对不起
Sorry
妈的！现在该你还钱
You should pay back!
喂！你用得着那么凶吗？
No need to be like that
不还钱我毁你容啊！
Pay me back, or I'll ruin your face
我上个月不是已经还你了吗？
I paid you back last month
还了？对对对已经还了！
Really? Yes, yes
你老了，记忆力衰退了
You're old. You lost your memory
算了，刚刚是我先不对嘛
Forget it, it's my fault
割了吧！都烧焦了
Cut it! Cut it!
脆了点！总比没有好
That's better zxa than nothing
明刀明枪跟他们拼了
Fight with him! Bros!
兄弟们，现身
Bros, let's go!
是
Yes!
两只妖怪，出来受死吧！
Devils, come out!
我的乾坤袋到哪里去了？
Where is the Magic Bag?
乾坤袋在这里，主人，他们想害你
The Magic Bag is here. They wanna frame you
吃里扒外，你出卖我们？
Traitor, you betray me
不过他今天能出卖我
Today, you betray me
明天也能够出卖你们
I will betray you one day
是吗？
Really?
是啊！
Yes!
我菩提老祖为了伏妖除魔
I want to destroy all devils
三角裤都脱了
I can take off my underwear!
帮主果然有眼光，二当家真的有问题
Master, there's really something wrong with Asst. Master
这老小子平常叫他做事，推三阻四
That guy is unwilling to do anything even if I beg him
今次这么爽快，一定有问题
Now, he admit so quickly. There must be something wrong
把他拖出来
Pull him out
是！
Yes!
放开我
Let me go…
Let me go
少啰嗦
Shut up
放开我⋯
Let me go
跪下
Kneel down
你这叛徒，今天晚上把你杀了烤来吃
You son of a bitch, I'm gonna kill you tonight
好！
Fine!
这个也不能怪他
You can't blame him
他只不过是中了两个妖女的移魂大法
He's only mesmerized by both devils
放了我！
Let me go
不然我叫我主人杀了你们
or I'll tell my Master to kill you
你还敢多！
Shut up!
旺财
Wong Choi
你咬着的绳子我怎么觉得好面熟啊？
The string you're biting is so familiar
奇怪
Stranger
就是我绑乾坤袋条的绳子
It is the string for my Magic Bag
死老头
Son of a bitch
天堂有路你不走，地狱无门你闯进来
How dare you come here!
来吧！
Come here!
让我掐死你个托世孙悟空
I'll kill you, reincarnated Monkey King
你就永远都找不到唐三藏了
Then you won't find the Longevity Monk
什么？
What?
他是孙悟空？
He is the Monkey King?
你要暂时冒充啊
Say you're the Monkey King
不然我们就完蛋去了
or we'll all die
他不是孙悟空
He's not the Monkey King
他连我三味白骨火都受不了
He can't even withstand my Skeleton Fire
怎么会是孙悟空呢？
He is not the Monkey King
玩笑开大了吧？
Shit!
这种天机你也敢泄露出来？
You've exposed a top secret
你疯了吗？
Really?
这一边
This way
你算是个神仙吗你
Are you really a fairy?
把手拿过来
Give me your hand
过份⋯
It is too much of you…
你以为我真的怕你的三味白骨火吗？
Do you think I can't withstand your Skeleton Fire?
你再烧一次试试看
Burn me again
来真的？
Serious?
好！
Great!
我不怕啦！对不对？
I'm not scared! See?
对啊！
Yes!
我孙悟空就一直把手放在这里让你烧
You can burn my hand if you like
让他们见识，见识！
I'm not afraid of you
不就是烧手吗？
Not burn my hand?
焦了
Burning
真的烧焦了也没有事
The hand is still OK
放手！
Let go!
你现在知道我真的啦
Now you know I'm great
快点投降
Surrender!
我还有一班兄弟，再加上一个神仙
I have got my bros and a fairy
你到哪里去了呀？
Where are you going?
我改天帮你报仇
I'll take revenge on you one day
哗！连神仙都不讲义气
Even a fairy is not righteous
那不用说了
No need to ask
我那帮兄弟一定站到那边去了
My bros must be there
是的，帮主！
Yes! Master!
唉！一群大白痴
Sons of bitches!
你就是那个负心人？
Are you that heartless guy?
昨天晚上骗我！
You deceived me last night!
可恶的臭猴子
That Monkey King
我师妹嫁不出去就是因为你
Sister will not be married just because of you
我？
Me?
抓住至尊宝！
Get the Joker!
上！
Go!
不要乱来！
Stop that
帮主快跑呀
Master, go
不要杀我的兄弟呀
Don't kill my bros!
帮主
Master
瞎子，不用怕，有我在
Blindy, I'm here, no need to scare me
对不起啊，瞎子！
Sorry, Blindy!
今次算了少走了一步
You have made a mistake
你不会怪我吧？
You won't blame me, will you?
我一辈子⋯　　我知道
For my whole life I know
都是个瞎子
I'm blind…
我最有眼光就是跟着帮主
But I am right to be your follower!
我跟你们拼了
Kill you!
去死吧你
You go to hell
不能杀这个负心人
You can't kill him
你还帮着他
You still help him
还要靠他找唐僧的
You want to rely on him to find the Longevity Monk
带他回盘丝洞
Take him back to Spider's Web Cave
师姐
Sister
一个和尚有水喝，两个和尚没水喝
Only one man can benefit from it
这个道理原来你不懂
You don't know this in fact
你打伤我，也不见得一定有水喝
You won't gain anything even if you hurt me
你自己看看手掌
Look at your palm
黑寡妇
Black Widow!
你中了我的盘丝软甲毒
You've been poisoned by my weapon
七日之内没有我的解药
You will die in 7 days
你就会毒气攻心而死
if you can't get my remedy
师姐，我再也不敢了
Sister, I don't dare to do so anymore
滚开！
Get lost!
终于良心发现了你
You regret at last
不是啦！外面来了个更狠的
No! A fierce thing has come
出去看看
Go out and have a look
你们上哪去？
Where are you going?
别去啊
No!…
牛魔王也来了？
King Bull has come?
牛魔王？
King Bull?
你也装死啊？
Pretend to be dead here?
我也是
Me too…
怪兽
Monster
菩提老祖
Grandpa Buddha
今日不把唐三藏交出来
Give the Longevity Monk to me
死路一条
or you're gonna die
少废话！
We have nothing to talk about
你问托世孙悟空嘛
You are looking for the Monkey King
我结拜老弟孙悟空？
My bro Monkey King?
在哪？
Where is he?
这个更凶狠的
This monster
原来是孙悟空的结拜大哥
is the Monkey King's Bro
这次有救了
We are saved
小弟就是结拜大哥你的
I'm you Bro
结拜弟弟孙悟空托世
the reincarnated Monkey King
是你？
You?
是⋯
Yes…
正是小弟
Yes! It's me
我杀了你这个勾引二嫂的王八蛋！
I'm gonna kill you adulterer!
何方妖女！报上名来
Tell me your name, witch!
盘丝大仙座下大弟子白骨精
I'm Boney M of Spider Devil
蜘蛛精
Spider Woman
我认识你们祖师盘丝大仙的时候
In the old days when I knew your masters
你们两个还不知道在哪里？
where were you?
今天居然敢跟我放肆
I have no business with you…
变⋯
Change…
今天有谁敢挡我
I'm going to kill
我就杀了谁
the ones who block my way
尝尝我的白骨鞭！
Try my White Bone Whip!
变
Change!
神龙盘丝
Dragon Heavenly Silk!
快走！
Go!
雕虫小技
It's only a small trick
瞎子，你不是死了吗？
Blindy, you're still alive!
我们刚刚是装死的
We are in trouble
我服了你
I admire you
不要走呀⋯
Don't go…
看看你们还有什么法宝？
Let me see what magic you have got
死牛魔王　　走
King Bull Go
他打伤了我菩提根
My Little Buddha is hurt
起码得练上一百八十年才能跟他们斗
Another hundred years before it is healed
起床了！
Get up
你干什么？
What are you doing?
我主人要见你
Master wanna see you
这是什么地方？
What place is this?
盘丝洞
Spider Web Cave
盘丝洞？
Spider Web Cave?
对！
Yes!
我主人是盘丝大仙座下大弟子蜘蛛精
I'm Spider Devil's disciple Spider Woman
这里不是盘丝洞是什么？
This is Spider Web Cave
盘丝洞？
Spider Web Cave?
走吧，臭猴子！
Let's go! Monkey
你疯啦
Hey, you have gone mad
我是你的帮主呀，臭猴子！
I'm your Master, monkey!
我是疯了
I'm mad
可是你还在装傻
You are lying!
在山寨已经承认了
You've admitted that
自己是齐天大圣了嘛
you're the Monkey King
走吧
Go!
你聪明点
Get smart just for once
我是被逼暂时假装的
I was forced to pretend
不相信你拿个照妖镜看看我是不是？
you can use the Magic Mirror to show my true identity
照妖镜？
Magic Mirror?
看到了吧，看到了没有？
Can you see it?
看到了！
Yes
清楚吗？
Clear?
骗我！
Deceive me!
这个根本就不是照妖镜
This is not the Magic Mirror
猪呀！
Pig!
师姐，你可怜我吧
Sister, have pity on me
你急什么
Stay calm
在这段时间只要你乖乖的听话
I guarantee that you can trust
我保证你无事
my word this time
主人！
Master!
主人呀！
主人呀！臭猴子来了
Master! The monkey has come
唐三藏究竟在哪里？臭猴子
Where is the Longevity Monk?
好大的误会呀
Big misunderstanding, everybody
这个误会大到怎样？
How big?
我偷偷地跟你们说
Let me tell you secretly
我真是属猴，不过其实就不是猴子
I was born in the Year of Monkey, but I'm not the Monkey King
不用说了！
A waste of time!
我照妖镜又有，什么都有
I have got the Magic Mirror and everything
你用来照照看
You can use the mirror on me
假的，假的
Fake mirror
假的你都也敢⋯
how dare you use the fake mirror…
你不要再装蒜呀
Now! Stop playing game
如果我真是孙悟空
If I'm the Monkey King
我就不会被你咬住只手
why am I standing here for you to bite my hand?
一个跟斗飞上天
I could jump to the sky
然后在你们天灵盖拉个屎
Then shit on your heads
你现在没变真身
You haven't changed to be Monkey King yet
到时你以为你不会
You'll shit at that time
怎么样？师妹
What is it, sister?
心痛呀？
Broken hearted?
不是呀！
No
不是？
No?
我不会再为这个男人心痛
I won't be hurt by this man again
你欺骗我！
you are lying to me!
师姐，我没有骗你
Sister, I'm not lying to you
没有骗我？那你一剑杀了他吧
Then kill him
杀了他
Kill him
那你不想找唐三藏吗？
Don't you want to find the Longevity Monk?
想呀！但是我不相信你会一剑杀了他
Yes! But I don't think you will kill him
都不准⋯
Not accurate…
把剑给他！
Give the sword!
给他吧！　　知道！
Give! Understand
杀他！
Kill him!
你刺中我大腿呀
You've sliced a piece of my thigh out
我是故意的
I intended to do that
那你要赔偿我医药费呀？
Give me a bill and I'll pay you back
不用客气
You're welcome
我要杀你！
I kill you!
贱人，早知道你对臭猴子余情未了
Cheap whore, you still love that monkey
废话少说，干掉你
Stop that, I'm gonna kill you
没事吗？
Are you OK?
在危急时刻仍这样关心我
You're still concerned about me
从现在开始，爱你一百年
I'm gonna love forever onwards
在外面
They are outside
这门安全不安全呀？
Can this door block them?
这门是祖师爷用万年金刚石做的
this door is made of unbreakable steel
走开
Stand aside
师妹，你不记得他以前怎么对你啦？
Sister, do you remember how he treated you in the past?
他欺骗感情，背弃婚约
He deceived you, refused to marry you
你原本跟赤炼神君有段美好的姻缘
You had a good marriage with Chilian Immortal
都被他搞坏了
He ruined it
他现在还没本事
He can do nothing now
等他回复真身之后
When he returned to his own image
一样不理你的
he'll leave you
你他妈的有完没完啊？
Have you finished? Son of a bitch!
臭猴子，你敢骂我！
Damn monkey, how dare you call me a bitch!
我就骂你怎么样？
Scold me, son of a bitch
你别以为躲在里面很安全
Don't think it's safe to hide inside
今天是十五月圆之夜
it's full moon tonight
到时候她尸变，你死得难看
She will become a zombie!
我是吓大的
I don't scare, son of a bitch
什么？
What?
大王，这里有几千个山，山洞又多
There are many hills and caves here
不知道哪个才是盘丝洞的入口？
We don't know where the Spider Web Cave is?
是啊⋯
Yes…
是吗？比我身上的牛虱还多，给我找
More than the bugs in my body. Search!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
里面怎么样？死了没有？
How about inside? Are you fine?
你死了我们都不会死
Of course I'm alright
我们是快乐得不得了
We are very happy
晶晶姑娘美得一塌糊涂
Jing Jing is still very pretty
我是帅得乱七八糟
I'm still very handsome
我俩是俊男美女
We are still very good-looking
吃饭了三十娘
Meal time, Ma'am, 30th
救命呀
Help…
尸变了
Zombie!
开门
Open the door!
开不了呀
I can't open it!
嘴对嘴过点阳气给她
Kiss her, breath life to her
这样子可以阻止她一下
Maybe it will be stopped
吓死我了！
Scare me!
师妹，你斗不过我的
Sister, you can't defeat me
是吗？
Really?
你动一下我就扭断你的脖子
I'll break your neck if you move
快拿钥匙！把她关进去
Give me the key! Lock him up
你这么爱进去，是不是？
You wanna go inside
进去！
Now you can go
再见！
Goodbye!
冤冤相报何时了
Please stop taking revenge
我有个很好的建议
Listen to my suggestions
先说好，不准打脸
You can beat me, but please don't hit my face…
那里都别打啊，拜托！
Stop beat my cock, thanks
还有只鸡啊，三十娘
There is a chicken, Ma'am 30th
我叫你
I'm telling you
这样子亲他都没反应
No reactions after a kiss
你不要锁
Don't lock it up
好！你还不开门是吗？
Ok, since you refuse to open the door
我警告你
I warn you
我把你的心上人先奸后杀
I'll rape and kill your lover
One
Two
中
I get it
Three
催情大法
Seductive magic
你走
Go!
你干什么？
What are you doing?
我打了个冷颤
I have just shivered for a while
好过瘾啊
Very interesting
你在我身上打了个冷颤？
You shivered on my body?
是啊
Yes
我的天啊！
Oh god!
如果不是妖怪那有多好！
It must be better if she's not a devil!
你中的毒越来越深
You're poisoned
再不解，会死的
You'll die if you don't get cured
解了又怎样？
What for even if I'm cured?
不开心，长生不死也没用
Living long is meaningless if you are unhappy
开心，就算只能活几天已足够了
Your last few days will be great if you're happy
如果我告诉你我不是孙悟空
If I tell you I'm the Monkey King
你会怎么样？
what do you think?
我会杀了你
I will kill you
我真的不是孙悟空
I'm not him
这块真的是照妖镜
This is a magic mirror.
你照照看就知道了
You should use it
什么？你不是他？
You're not him, really?
不是
I'm not
你不怕我杀了你吗？
Don't you fear that I will kill you?
怕！不过没办法
Yes, but I have no option
因为我不希望你看着我的时候
Because I don't want you to look at me
心里面却想着另外一个人
while you're thinking of another
我把你给杀了
I would like to kill you
就像你说的，做人不开心
You said living long was meaningless
就算长生不死也没有用
if you were unhappy
来吧！
Go ahead!
来就来！
Yes, I'll
他母亲的，是谁绑得那么紧？
Shit! Who made this knot?
我来解！
Let me do it!
对不起，我不是故意的
Sorry, I don't mean it
我是看你那么冲动
You do it strongly
配合你一下而已！
So I wanna do it with you
我虽然不是什么正人君子
Although I'm not a righteous man
但也不至于乘人之危
I won't take advantage of the others
白天我不习惯
I'm not used to doing it at daytime
晚上再说
Let's wait till night
晚上也好，白天也好
No matter when
你随时需要，随时吩咐
call me if you need me
从今天开始
From now on
我会一直陪着你
I'll be with you
找到没有？
Can you get him?
没有
No
继续找吧
Go on
老天瞎了眼
Damn!
我春三十娘貌美如花
I'm so pretty
居然跟这么丑的男人有了
But I have a baby with such an ugly man
三十娘
Ma'am 30th
你闭嘴！
Shut up!
要不是为肚子，我早就打死你
I will kill you if I'm not pregnant
谢谢
Thanks
你那么开心干什么？
Why are you so happy?
我警告你⋯
Tell you …
将来他长大了
Don't tell the baby
你不许承认他的⋯那个
you're his father
那我算什么？
What should I be?
奶妈呀？
His maiden
我是男人怎么做奶妈啊？
I'm a man. I can't be a maiden!
孩子是我们带大的
We bring him up
你不说，他怎么知道男人不能做奶妈？
He doesn't know if a maiden is a man or a woman
那倒也是
That's right
我找到一个很像你的人
I've found a guy just like you
是你？
It's you?
想不想知道唐三藏在哪里？
Do you wanna know where the Longevity Monk is?
想
Yes, I do
想就别还手
Don't strike back if you do
要吃唐僧肉总要付出一点代价
you have to pay for the flesh of the Longevity Monk
值得！
It is worth it!
如果你肯给我解药救白晶晶
If you give me the medication for Jing Jing
我就告诉你唐僧在哪里
I will tell you where the Longevity Monk is
又是为了那个贱人
You just do it for that bitch
不爽呀？
I like to do so
奶妈
Maiden
奶妈疼你啊
Maiden is kissing you
我爽了，明天出发吧
Ok, let's go by tomorrow
为了爱情
Because of love
就算你真的毁我容，也是值得的
you can ruin my face if you like
快点，到底救不救人？
Hurry up, do you wanna save someone?
你得让我上马啊
Just let me do it!
至尊宝
Joker
你再不快点，师妹就不行了
Sister can't take this anymore. You go ahead!
你得让我上马才行呀
Let me… do that
不见了
Not here
全都是骗我
Everyone deceives me
过了这座山就回到菩提洞了
We'll reach the Buddha Cave after climbing this hill
不要呀，呀⋯
No, Ah!
晶晶！
Jing Jing!
一定以为我丢下她不管了
She thought I left her alone
还要找多久呀？
How long will you search?
晶晶
Jing Jing
毒发滚下山咯！
She's poisoned, must have died and fallen down from the cliff
讨厌，就是因为你
It's all because of you
为什么让我睡一个晚上？
You shouldn't let me sleep for a whole night
不连夜赶来
I should come here as soon as possible
你为什么不快马加鞭？
You should whip the horse strongly
我一定跟得上
We can be faster!
你别希望我把唐僧的告诉你
I won't tell you where the Longevity Monk is
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything
你自己走得慢还怪我？
How dare you put the blame on me!
什么？
What?
大王，我们发现白晶晶昏倒山崖
We discovered that Boney M fainted under the cliff
菩提老祖重伤不治
Grandpa Buddha has died
天助我也！
God is helping me!
进去！
Go in!
你不说出来
If you don't tell me
这一辈子都别指望出去
you can't go out
懒得理你
I won't listen to you
地也不是那么硬，有办法
The ground is not so hard
盖世魔王，神功护体
Powerful devil, extraordinary energy!
我把你的伤治好
I will cure your wound but
你要带我去盘丝洞找托世的猴子
you must take me to the Cave to get the incarnated monkey
我就可以找到唐僧
We'll find the Longevity Monk sooner or later
到时候吃唐僧肉少不了你的份
You can also eat the flesh of the Longevity Monk
否则我要你死得比现在痛苦十倍
or you will die painfully
挖隧道我也要离开这里
I have to come out even if I have to dig a tunnel
借助月亮光华可以穿梭时空
I can move freely in time and space with the power of the moon
什么东西呀？
What is it?
般若波罗蜜，是梵文啊
This is the Indian language
月光宝盒
The Pandora's Box
盘丝大仙留下来的宝物？
The treasure left behind by Spider Web Devil?
快带我进盘丝洞
Take me into the Cave
怎么肚子有点痛呀？
Why does the belly feel painful?
是不是要生啦？
Is it coming?
把我转那儿去了？
Where am I?
这么多机关？
Why so many traps?
越走越湿呢！
It becomes wetter and wetter
大王，你回来了？
Welcome, our King!
撞鬼啦我
Damn! I've met a ghost!
你装成这个样子干什么？
What's going on?
你喜欢唐三藏
You love the Longevity Monk
我扮成他让你开心嘛
so I play him to make you happy
你干什么嘛？
What are you doing?
我帮你接生呀
I'm helping you to give birth!
头出来了
The head is coming out!
是吗？我怎么没感觉？
Really, I've no feeling.
你看啦？
You see?
原来是我的菠萝盖！
This is my knee
怪不得没有头发啦
So there is no hair
有人来了
Someone's coming
先躲一躲，躲一躲！
Hide up, be quick
好痛呀
I'm hurt
我也好痛呀
I'm hurt, too
求求你把你的手放开好不好？
Please let go of my hand! Alright!
观世音
Goddess
孙悟空，你当年罪恶滔天
Monkey King, you've committed serious offences
希望你今生会大彻大悟，痛改前非
I hope you know you're wrong
谁在说话？
Who's talking?
五百年前你师父唐三藏为了赎你一命
500 years ago, your master Longevity Monk sacrificed
牺牲了他自己
his life to save you
玉皇大帝特意安排你
Heaven Emperor planned that
五百年后重投人间
you revive after 500 years
希望你能学你师父一样
I hope you'll be like your master
舍己为人
Making sacrifices to save the others
把你过往的一切罪孽洗清
To clean the sin that you've made before
只要你肯自愿带上金刚圈
You should put on the Gold Ring on your head
肯改过自新
Admit you sin
你就可以变回法力无边的齐天大圣
Then you'll become the super Monkey King
到时候你就要负起取西经的重任
You'll take the responsibility to get scriptures in the west
把历史重改
Rewrite the history
不过从此人间一切与你无关
All things in human life are then none of your business
再不可能有半点情欲，半点留恋
you can't have any desires anymore
要全心归依我佛
Worship Buddha whole-heartedly
你还没变成真正的孙悟空托世
You haven't turned into the Monkey King
只系因为你还没遇上
because you haven't met the guy
那个给你三颗痣的人
who gives you the 3 birthmarks
当你遇到他之后
After you see him
你的一生就会改变
your whole life will be changed
跟我说话吗？
Talking to me?
不是跟我说的吧？
I don't think so
认错人啦
I think you have made a mistake
神经病！
Crazy!
好痛呀⋯
Painful…
放手呀
Let go!
你安静点行不行？　　不行⋯
Keep calm please No
安静呀
Keep calm
呀！好痛呀
I'm painful
我也一样痛呀！
I'm painful, too
小心机关
Mind the traps here
追
Chase
走呀
Go!
快拉住我呀
Come here and grab me
抓住了⋯ ，生了⋯
Ok, do it…Ok! It's coming
唐三藏出世了，快找
The Longevity Monk was born, go to get him!
是！
Yes!
是男的！长得很像你呀
The baby looks like you
我觉得
I think
做不做神仙
being an immortal or not is not important
能不能吃到唐僧肉并不重要
The flesh of the Longevity Monk isn't must, too
最重要的是我们以后能好好的生活
We have to live together happily
把孩子带大
Bring our son up
不要像我一样当山贼
Don't let him be robber
你那么想要唐僧
You want the Longevity Monk most
干脆儿子就叫做三藏好了
Just call him Longevity
谁？
Who?
我们可算是冤家路窄了
It is too coincident
你想怎么样？
What do you want?
孩子是你的？
Your baby?
没错，是我跟至尊宝生的
My baby with Joker!
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
奶妈，你告诉她吧！
Maiden, tell him
你说呀！
Tell him!
是！
Yes!
她跟至尊宝生的
this is her baby with Joker
走
Go!
看你往哪跑？
See where you can go
不用怕，我保护你
No need to scare, I'm gonna protect you
你知不知道你什么身份啊？
Who the hell are you?
凭什么保护我？
You're not qualified to protect me
滚开
Get lost
把我儿子抱走
take my son away
过来呀！
Come here!
把唐三藏给我
Give me the Longevity Monk
我不是让你过来啊
I'm not calling you to come
这是我儿子呀
This is my son
不是唐三藏
not the Longevity Monk
救命呀
Help!
救命呀⋯
Help…
你这么关心我，我愿意为你精尽人亡
You're concerned about me, I'll die for you
带我儿子走！
Take my son away
不走
Don't go!
走
Go
三十娘
Ma'am, 30th
总算跑出来了
It is lucky that we can go out
晶晶
Jing Jing
老婆
Honey
龟缩大法
Tortoise Magic
我割你的肝！割你的胃！
Slash your liver, stomach
我割你的心脏！割你的肺！
and internal organs!
打个蝴蝶结
Tie it with a knot
〝元神出窍〞
“Here comes the spirit”
贱人！别再踩我的肠子啦
Bitch, don't step on my intestine
喜欢！我要踩
I wanna do so
老婆⋯！
Honey…!
我老婆在里面
My wife is inside
拜托你帮帮忙！
Please help me!
没有空！
I'm not free
拜托啦！
Thanks!
出来啦！
Come out!
走
Go!
是不是真的能时光倒流？
Can we go back to the past?
快走，走！
Hurry up! Go!
我不走！要走一起走！
I won't! Let's go together
你听我说
Listen to me
好好带大我们的孩子
Bring up my son
走呀！
Go!
我们的孩子！娘子！
Our son! Honey!
你再不走我就死给你看
you have to leave or I'll die!
不要啊！
No!
娘子⋯
Honey…Honey…
相公！
Honey!
月光快出来啊！
the moon is rising!
娘子
Honey
好！
Ok!
波罗什么玩意忘光光了
What's that? I've forgot that!
般若波罗蜜⋯！
Boyi Bolomi…
升仙了！
Being immortal!
帅呀！这下时光倒流了！
Great! We're going back to the past
等等⋯
Wait for me!
凶手跑得那么快？再来！
The killer is leaving
老婆⋯我老婆
Honey…My wife
你老婆就快出来了，你急什么？
Your wife is coming out, easy!
我还没说完，你是怎么知道的？
I've not finished. How do you know?
真的出来了　　走呀
She's coming out. Go!
娘子⋯
Honey, honey…
般若波罗蜜！
Boyi Bolomi!
又升仙了！
Being immortal again!
为什么又说〝又〞呢？
Why did you say “again”?
等等⋯！
Wait…
再来！
Again!
老婆⋯！
Honey…!
我警告你别烦我！
Don't disturb me!
为什么要我别烦你？还要警告我？
Why did you tell me not to disturb you?
你真是啰嗦啊
Shit! You're annoying!
是啊！我也觉得自己很啰嗦
I know I'm annoying
为什么？
Why?
出来啦！
You come out!
走，走呀！
Go, go!
娘子⋯
Honey…
般若波罗蜜⋯
Boyi Bolomi
〝拷〞你也够撑了
You're also very annoying
等等⋯
Wait…
我的妈呀，累死我了
Damn, I'm very tired
老婆⋯
Honey…
拿来
Give me
我懒得跟你说！
I won't tell you!
懒得跟我说就不要说啊
That's fine
为什么要打我呢？
Why did you do so?
娘子⋯
Honey…
般若波罗蜜⋯
Boyi Bolomi…
娘子呀，跟牛魔王出来看上帝
Honey, come out with King Bull and see Jesus
刀下留人！
Stop!
原来是自杀
Commit suicide
你为什么要自杀？
Why commit suicide?
自杀？要死也先杀了你
No, I prefer killing you!
英雄！
Hero!
你放过我吧
You let me go!
放过你？
Let you go?
你给一个不杀你的理由
Tell me a reason why I have to let you go
正在想！你先给我一个杀我的理由
You tell me a reason why you wanna kill me
好呀！你一声不响丢下我
Ok, you leave me alone
还跟师姐生了个儿子！
and you have a baby with my sister
你完全误会了　　找死？
No, that's not the case Wanna die?
不要啊，英雄！
No, hero!
我是跑回来跟你师姐拿解药去救你
I left because I wanna get medication for you from your sister
谁知道晚了一步
But I was late
回去已经找不到你了
I couldn't find you
你骗我
You deceive me!
你不信
You don't trust me
你看
You look
他们到哪儿去了？
Where have they been?
怎么啦？
What's up?
你跑不掉的！
You can't leave!
断龙石关了便打不开快出去
When the rock is put down, the door is closed
娘子⋯
Honey…
让我来！
Let me do this
走呀！
Go!
至尊宝来生再见
Joker, see you in the next life
娘子⋯
Honey
相公⋯
Honey!
娘子⋯
Honey…
再来！
Again!
般若波罗蜜⋯
Boyi Bolomi…
晶晶！
Jing Jing
人呢？都到哪儿去了？
Where are they?
怎么会这样了？
What's going on?
神仙呀？
Immortal?
妖怪？
Devil?
谢谢！
Thanks!
盘丝洞不要乱闯！
Don't go into the Spider Web Cave!
盘丝洞？
Spider Web Cave?
你当我不识字呀？
You think I'm illiterate?
水帘洞呀！
Waterfall Cave
盘丝洞这个名也蛮好听的
Spider Web Cave. It is a good name
盘丝洞
Spider Web Cave
以后我就住在这儿
We'll live here from now on
等一等！
Stop!
我现在郑重宣布
I wanna announce
在这个山头所有东西都是我的
In this hill, all things belong to me
包括你在内
Including you
我？
Me?
是啊
yes
就像我的骡仔一样先给你盖个章吧！
you look like a donkey, let me make a mark on you
你现在是我的人了
You're mine now
如果有人欺负你，就报我的名字
If someone bullies you, you tell them you know me
从今日起，我叫盘丝大仙
I'm called Spider Web Immortal now!
盘丝大仙？
Spider Web Immortal?
五百年前？
500 years?
你没有变成孙悟空托世
You haven't turned into Monkey King
是因为你还没碰见给你三颗痣的人
because you haven't met the guy having three birthmarks
芝麻关门！
Close the door